oxfamindia.org 2012-06-24

# Privacy Policy | Oxfam India

Oxfam India is committed to safeguarding your privacy online. Our privacy policy applies to all the pages hosted on oxfamindia.org. It does not apply to pages hosted by other organizations to which we may link and whose might have different privacy policies. We do not collect personally identifiable information on our web site unless you voluntarily share it via website contact form, subscription, by signing up for a campaign, or by postal mail. Even this information is kept confidential, and our partners/ suppliers are also bound these conditions as well. 

We use this information to: 

• Maintain accurate details of our supporters' history with the organization 

• Process donations and provide receipts 

• Keep our supporters informed about our work 

• Send newsletters etc. to subscribers 

**1\. What personally identifiable information is collected from me?**

Oxfam India uses cookies to provide you with a more personalized web service. A cookie is a text-only string of information that we pass to your computer’s hard disk through your web-browser so that the website can remember who you are. Cookies cannot be used by themselves to identify you. A cookie will typically contain the name of the domain from which the cookie has come, the “lifetime” of the cookie, and a value, usually a randomly generated unique number. If you do not wish to receive cookies you can easily modify your web browser to refuse cookies, or to notify you when you receive a new cookie. However, you may not be able to use all the interactive features of our site if cookies are disabled. 

**2\. How does Oxfam India use my information?**

Oxfam India uses the information we collect about you to help us with understanding more about how our site is used and to be able to send you communications that may be of interest to you, either electronically or otherwise. Oxfam India may also monitor which websites you have come from prior to entering the Oxfam India site and which websites you move on to after leaving the Oxfam India site. We use this information to assess the impact of, and develop adverts and campaigns. 

**3\. Who is collecting your information?**

When you are on the Oxfam India website and are asked for personal information, you are sharing that information with Oxfam India alone unless stated otherwise. When you are using our secure online donation pages you are going through to the partner company and it is clear on the donation page when you are going through to the third party site. 

**4\. With whom does Oxfam India share your information?**

Oxfam India will not disclose any of your personally identifiable information, except when we have your permission or under special circumstances, such as when we believe in good faith that the law requires it. When you are using our secure online donation pages you are going through to a partner company and the information you give such as your credit card number and contact information is provided so that the transaction can take place. 

**5\. What are my choices regarding, collection, use and distribution of my information?**

If you indicated that you are interested in receiving regular information about Oxfam India’s campaign work or emergencies appeals we will send you communications regarding Oxfam India’s work and activities, either electronically or otherwise. In addition, we may send you direct mail that we feel may be of interest to you. Oxfam India does not sell, rent or share user information with anyone. We may on occasion work with 3rd parties to contact our supporters about Oxfam India, however, the 3rd party would also be bound by a confidentiality agreement which would prevent them from using this information for any other purpose. 

**6\. What is Oxfam India’s policy on allowing me to update, correct, or delete my personally identifiable information?**

The accuracy of your individual identifying information is important to Oxfam India. We are working on ways to make it easier for you to review and correct the information that Oxfam India maintains about you. In the meantime, if you change email address or any of the other information we hold is inaccurate or out of date, please email us at [fundraising@oxfamindia.org](mailto:fundraising@oxfamindia.org)

**7\. How does Oxfam India protect my personal identifiable information?**

Oxfam India is committed to taking reasonable steps to protect the individual identifying information that you provide to us. 

**8\. What security precautions are in place to protect the loss, misuse, or alteration of my information?**

When you share personal information with Oxfam India, we take all the possible steps to ensure that your information is treated securely. While we strive to protect your personal information, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. Oxfam India cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us but we make our best effort to ensure its security on our systems. 

**9\. Is the Online Payment Gateway secure?**

Our Donation form page uses Secure Sockets Layer (SSL): a security protocol that provides communications privacy over the Internet. This encrypts all of your personal information, including credit card number, name, and address, so that it cannot be read as the information travels over the Internet. While on a secure page, such as our giving form, the lock icon on the bottom of your web browser becomes locked, as opposed to un-locked, or open, when you are just 'surfing'. While we use SSL encryption to protect sensitive information online, we also do everything in our power to protect user-information off-line. All of your information, not just the sensitive information like a credit card number, is restricted. Only the employees who need the information to perform a specific job (for example, our donation officers) are granted access to personally identifiable information. Furthermore, all employees who handle membership information are kept up-to-date on our security and privacy practices. And they are well aware of the importance we place on privacy, and what they can do to ensure our supporters' information is protected. 

**We have tried to answer all possible concerns above; should you have any additional concerns in relation to Oxfam India and your privacy, we will be glad to address them promptly and advise you of your rights.**

 **Terms and Conditions**

We as a merchant shall be under no liability whatsoever in respect of any loss or damage arising directly or indirectly out of the decline of authorization for any Transaction, on Account of the Cardholder having exceeded the preset limit mutually agreed by us with our acquiring bank  from time to time"
